* JP
* EN

閉じる

プライバシーポリシー
==========

### 1\. 個人情報保護理念

1.1 株式会社Live2D（以下、「当社」といいます。）は、個人情報保護の重要性と社会的責任についてよく認識し、その取扱いに細心の注意を払うとともに、お預かりする個人情報を厳正に取り扱います。

1.2 当社は、取得目的を明確にしたうえで、目的の範囲内に限り個人情報を取得します。また、個人情報の利用はその取得目的から逸脱しない範囲とし、目的外利用は行いません。

1.3 個人情報の取り扱いに関するルールを明確にしてこれを従業者に周知徹底し、個人情報の保護に努めます。また、個人情報の漏洩、紛失等を防止するのに必要な対策を講じ、適切に管理します。

### 2\. 利用目的等

当社は、個人情報を取得する場合、以下に定める目的の範囲内でのみ利用するものとし、本人の同意なく正当な目的の範囲を超えて利用しません。ただし、法的な要請や生命の危機・公衆衛生の向上等、緊急事態の場合その他法令で許容されている場合は除きます。

2.1 当社取り扱いサービス、製品の営業活動（企画、開発、販売、提供、サポート、メンテナンス等）

2.2 当社取り扱いサービス、製品の広告宣伝活動（ＰＲ、キャンペーン、イベント、アンケート調査等）

2.3 当社取り扱いサービス、製品に係る連絡（情報提供、受注・発注、代金の請求・受領・支払、お問い合わせに対する回答等）

2.4 従業者（採用応募者、退職者を含む）の雇用、採用等の人事労務管理

2.5 その他上記各業務に付帯する業務の実施

### 3\. 第三者提供

当社は、業務を円滑に進めるため業務の一部を外部委託する場合がありますが、この場合は業務委託先との間で個人情報の取り扱いに関する契約を締結する等、必要かつ適切な措置を講じて個人情報の保護に努めます。 また、業務委託先への提供の場合のほか、以下に該当する場合に限り、個人情報を第三者に提供することがあります。

3.1 本人の同意がある場合

3.2 司法機関・行政機関等から法令に基づき開示・提供を求められた場合

3.3 合併、会社分割、事業譲渡その他の事由により事業の継承が行われる場合

3.4 人の生命・身体または財産の保護のため必要がある場合であって、本人の同意を得ることが困難な場合

3.5 統計的なデータ等、本人を識別できない状態で開示・提供する場合

3.6 国または地方公共団体等が法令の定める事務を遂行することに対して協力する必要がある場合であって、本人の同意を得ることにより当該事務の遂行に支障を及ぼす恐れがある場合

3.7 その他法令で許容されている場合または正当な事由に基づく場合

### 4\. 個人情報の開示・訂正・削除等のお問い合わせ

当社にて保有する個人情報につきましては、保有個人データの本人またはその代理人から開示・訂正・削除等のご請求に対応させていただいております。開示・訂正、削除等をご希望される場合は、担当窓口宛にご連絡いただきますようお願いします。なお、お問い合わせの際、本人またはその代理人であることや、当社との取引状況等を確認させていただく場合があります。ご請求があった場合には、合理的な期間及び範囲で適切に対応いたします。

### 5\. 適用および変更

本プライバシーポリシーは、当社が取得した個人情報のみに適用されます。当社は、法令変更もしくは個人情報保護の改善等の理由から、随時本プライバシーポリシーを変更することがあり、プライバシーポリシーの変更は、それが当社のウエブサイトに掲載された日から有効となります。なお、当社のウエブサイトとのリンク先のプライバシー保護については当社は責任を負いかねますので、それぞれのリンク先のプライバシーポリシー等をご確認ください。

### 6\. Cookieの利用について

6.1 当社のウエブサイトでは第三者が提供するアクセス解析ツールを使用しています。この解析ツールはデータの収集のためにCookieを使用しています。このデータは匿名で収集されており個人を特定するものではありません。解析に当たっては、解析ツールを提供する第三者にもこのデータが提供され、広告配信に用いられることがあります。

6.2 前項において第三者が取得する情報は、当該第三者のプライバシーポリシーに基づき管理されます。また、第三者によるCookie情報の取得を明示的に回避したい場合は当該第三者の定める手続きによりCookieを無効化できます。当社が利用しているお主なツール提供会社は以下の通りであり、そのプライバシーポリシーとCookieを無効化する手続きは以下の通りです。

6.2.1 Google Inc.

Googleプライバシーポリシー

Googleアナリティクスオプトアウトアドオン

6.3 当社は第三者配信事業者と広告の配信について提携することがあります。当社のウエブサイトを閲覧された方に対して、第三者配信事業者がCookieを用いて当社のウエブサイトへの過去のアクセス情報を利用する場合があります。このアクセス情報は匿名で収集され個人を特定するものでありません。

6.4 当社が利用している主な第三者配信事業者は以下のとおりであり、その広告に関するポリシーおよび広告の配信停止の方法は以下の通りです。

6.4.1 Google Inc.

Googleプライバシーポリシー

Google広告設定

### 7\. お客様へのお願い

7.1 お客様の個人情報や通信記録に他人がアクセスすることがないように、当社取り扱いサービス等にログインし、アクセスした後は常にログアウトするように心がけてください。また、パスワードや会員情報等は秘密にしておいてください。もしお客様自身のアカウントに不正にアクセスされた場合には、速やかに当社にご連絡ください。

7.2 当社取り扱いサービス等において、お客様が能動的に、当社取り扱いサービス等を利用する他のお客様等に知らせる目的で開示する個人的連絡先情報に関しては、当社は一切責任を負いませんので、お客様ご自身による個人情報の公開は、お客様の自己の責任の範囲内で行い、公開レベルを設定、管理するようお願いいたします。お客様が自ら公開する個人情報は、それが収集され、他人によって使用されることがあることにご留意ください。

### 8\. 言語間の相違

本プライバシーポリシーの日本語版と他の言語の翻訳版との間に齟齬がある場合には、日本語版が優先するものします。

以上

バージョン： 1.0

改定日： 2022年2月2日

(English Translation, see Section 8)

Privacy Policy
--------------

### 1\. Philosophy of Personal Information Protection

1.1 Live2D Inc. (hereinafter referred to as “Live2D”) acknowledges the importance and social responsibility of protecting personal information well, and handles personal information entrusted to us in a strict manner paying close attention.

1.2 Live2D will acquire personal information only within the scope of the purpose of acquisition after specifying it. Live2D will use personal information only within the scope of the purpose of acquisition, and will not use it for any other purpose.

1.3 Live2D shall endeavor to protect personal information by clarifying the rules for handling personal information and making every employee informed the rules. Live2D will take the necessary measures to prevent the leakage or loss of personal information, and manage it appropriately.

### 2\. Purpose of Use

Where Live2D acquires personal information, Live2D will use it only within the scope of the purposes specified below, and will not use it beyond the scope of legitimate purposes without the consent of the individual. However, this does not apply to legal requests cases, emergencies such as life threatening or public health improvement, or other cases permitted by law.

2.1 Sales activities for Live2D’s services and products (planning, development, sales, provision, support, maintenance, etc.)

2.2 Promotions for Live2D’s services and products (PR, campaigns, events, questionnaire surveys, etc.)

2.3 Communication related to Live2D’s services and products (provision of information, order placement, billing, receipt and payment, response to inquiries, etc.)

2.4 Personnel labor management, such as hiring or recruiting employees (including applicants for employment and retired employees)

2.5 Carrying out other operations related to operations set forth in the preceding items.

### 3\. Provision to A Third Party

Live2D may outsource part of its operation to implement the operation smoothly. In this case, Live2D will take necessary and appropriate measures to protect personal information, such as concluding a contract with the subcontractor regarding handling of the personal information. In addition to providing personal information to the subcontractors, Live2D may provide personal information to third parties only;

3.1 If Live2D obtains the prior consent of the person;

3.2 If Live2D is required by law or court order;

3.3 In the case of succession of business due to merger, corporate separation, business transfer or other reasons;

3.4 Cases in which the handling of the personal information is necessary for the protection of the life, body, or property of an individual and in which it is difficult to obtain the consent of the person;

3.5 Cases in which the disclosing or providing information in a manner that does not identify the individual such as statistical data format;

3.6 Cases in which the cooperation with execution of affairs prescribed by laws and/or regulations by a state organ, a local government is required and in which obtaining the consent of the person is likely to impede the execution of the affairs concerned; and

3.7 Cases permitted by law and/or regulations or based on legitimate reasons.

### 4\. Inquiries about Disclosure, Correction, Deletion, etc. of Personal Information

Live2D will disclose, correct, delete, etc. personal information Live2D possess within a reasonable period of time and scope upon request from the person or its representative. If you wish to disclose, correct, delete, etc. your personal data, please contact our contact in charge. Note that Live2D may verify personal identification of the person or its representative, and/or your trading records with Live2D.

### 5\. Application and Changes

This Privacy Policy applies only to personal information acquired by Live2D. Live2D may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time for reasons such as revisions of laws or attempt to improve the protection measures of personal information, and the modified Privacy Policy will be effective on the date posted on Live2D’s website. Since Live2D is not responsible for protections of privacy under other websites linked to Live2D’s website, confirmation of the privacy policies of those websites is highly recommended.

### 6\. Use of Cookies

6.1 Live2D uses an access analysis tool provided by a third party on its website. This analysis tool uses Cookies to collect data. The data are collected anonymously and does not identify the individual. In the course of analysis, such data are also provided to third parties who provide analysis tools, and may be used to the distribution of advertisements.

6.2 The information acquired by the third party in the preceding paragraph will be managed under the privacy policy of the third party.

If you explicitly wish to avoid the acquisition of Cookie information by a third party, you can disable Cookies by following the procedures specified by the third party. The main tool providers Live2D uses are listed below, and their privacy policies and procedures for disabling Cookies are as follows:

6.2.1 Google Inc.

Google privacy policy

Google analytics opt out add-on

6.3 Live2D may partner with third party service providers for the distribution of advertisements. Third party service providers may use Cookies to collect information about access to Live2D’s websites by persons. This access information is collected anonymously and does not identify the individual.

6.4 The main third party service providers Live2D uses are listed below, and their policies regarding advertisements and procedures for unsubscribing from advertising are as follows:

6.4.1 Google Inc.

Google privacy policy

Google advertising settings

### 7\. Request to You

7.1 In order to prevent others from accessing your personal information and communication records, please log out always after logging in and accessing to Live2D’s services in each case. Also, please keep your password and membership information confidential. If your account has been illegally accessed, please contact us immediately.

7.2 Live2D shall not be responsible for any personal contact information that is disclosed by you actively for the purpose of informing other customers who use Live2D services. Please disclose personal information within the scope of your own responsibility by setting and managing the disclosure level by yourself. Please note that any personal information you disclose may be collected and used by others.

### 8\. Difference between Languages

If any conflict between the Japanese version of this Privacy Policy and any translated version thereof arises, the Japanese version shall be the governing and prevailing version.

Ver. 1.0

Revised: February 2nd, 2022

© 2010 - 2024 Live2D Inc.
